<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Scott Anderson Design</title>
    <description></description>
    <link>http://www.scottandersonwebdesign.com/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://www.scottandersonwebdesign.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jun 2016 11:24:13 -0500</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 28 Jun 2016 11:24:13 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.1.2</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Past Inspiration</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I am currently knee deep in the middle of my final project, and it’s going to be a crunch to get what I want done in time. Luckily, I have found a form of inspiration to keep me going.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While coding I usually listen to music as I do so. I think it occupies that old ADHD side of my brain. But the form of music I usually listen to are broadway show tunes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Pause for subtle jokes at my expense.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lately the show I have been listening to a lot is &lt;em&gt;Hamilton&lt;/em&gt;. And for anyone who slightly follows the musical theater scene this is probably not surprising. I mean, it now holds the record for most Tony nominations in history (16). The show is sold out for the foreseeable future, and re-sale tickets are going for astronomical prices on StubHub and Ticketmaster.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The show is that dang good, so the main reason I listen to the soundtrack is for the pure enjoyment factor while I’m coding at the computer. The music is upbeat, enriching, and dynamic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;I hope someone talks about my designs that way…&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However it occured to me that there was more than one reason that I kept listening to this particular soundtrack. I love other broadway shows, and can just as easily listen to them instead. Yet, I find myself coming back to listen to &lt;em&gt;Hamilton&lt;/em&gt; time and time again. Why? Maybe because of the man himself, Alexander Hamilton.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A young up and comer, trying to prove himself in a land of giants. He worked hard, harder than most anyone else, in order to gain an advantage over them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In fact, one of the most engaging songs in the show is one titled, “My Shot.” In it, Hamilton exuberantly proclaims that he is not throwing away this shot he has: his shot to leave a legacy behind and make a name for himself and guarantee the freedom of our country for future descendants.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Gives me goosebumps everytime.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I sit and work on the final project it becomes easy at times for me to want to take too many breaks, or too long of breaks, or to just say, “You know what, I can work on this tomorrow.” But I stop myself from doing that…mostly by listening to this song. No, time for rest is later. You need to work hard now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The harder I practice, the luckier I get.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Time is going to be a crunch, as the deadline for getting the project done is fast approaching. And even though there is a lot of work left to be done between now and then, I am moving forward confidently. I have a lot to prove, and I look forward to the challenge.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Because I’m not throwing away my shot.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 16 May 2016 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.scottandersonwebdesign.com/2016/05/16/Past-Inspiration.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.scottandersonwebdesign.com/2016/05/16/Past-Inspiration.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Risk: Not Just a Board Game</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;This past Friday I had the opportunity to attend Creative Mornings in downtown Austin. Since then, I’ve had time to reflect on what I learned.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First of all, so much fun. To be honest, they had me committed when they spoke of coffee and breakfast tacos. Fuel and sustenance, gets me every time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not to mention, the opportunity to connect with others in the Austin community was insanely valuable. Many had heard of The Iron Yard and of other coding bootcamps in the city (MakerSquare, General Assembly, etc.) and were eager to hear about the process we go through. It was also nice to be provided words of encouragement and validation by some peers in the Austin area.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After hearing some great music by &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.uncleluciusmusic.com/&quot;&gt;Uncle Lucius&lt;/a&gt; we were welcomed by the team, and then broke out into two groups.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The fun twist that the Creative Mornings team offered this particular Friday was that after we broke into groups of two we did not know who our speaker was going to be. Henceforth, we were taking a risk. A risk not knowing who we would be listening too, and that we would have to have some faith in the team for providing us a great speaker, no matter who they were.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was lucky. I got the pleasure of hearing the personal story of &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.shapingsapiens.com/&quot;&gt;Amelia Torres&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Amelia did a wonderful job of telling us her personal devotional, being very open with us about her struggles with depression and her subsequent trips through South America and the United States.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just as we had taken a risk in not knowing who our guest speaker was going to be (albeit a small one), Amelia told us a gripping story of her past experiences in taking risks as well (much bigger ones).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She and a friend decided to take a trip along the cities and roads of South America in an old, beat down van. A van which would break down multiple times, require maintenance, and then conk out again somewhere down the road. Upon her return to Austin, she knew she had to “keep going.” And so she left her job, sold many of the things she owned, and began a long trip in her car all across the United States. So much inspiration.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Holy Cow that’s awesome.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After leaving, the wheels in my brain started turning. Mostly powered by too much complimentary coffee and perhaps a tinge of jealousy, I started wondering if I should take more risks in my life. Like Amelia did.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;But wait, what about coding? What about design and web development? What about Iron Yard?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Turns out, after some reflection, I am currently in the middle of a huge risk. After leaving my past careers in church and real estate, I decided to pursue a career in this thing called UI/UX Design. I applied and enrolled at Iron Yard. I left my home in Dallas and re-located to Austin for three months. I have to commute an hour and a half each day to class (both ways). My wife is back home.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Yeah….kind of a big risk.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m not pulling in any income at all during this time, and I am away from my wife. Yes, these past few months have been difficult. But even among the hardship, it has been great at the same time. I have become a web designer, and am growing more and more confident in my abilities each and every single day. I made new friends and connections since coming down here. I’m getting to work in Austin (kind of a cool city). And of course, there is the career as a web designer awaiting for me on the horizon. Yes I took a big risk, but man a lot of awesome things have happened already…and will continue to do so.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;No risk no reward, right?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 03 May 2016 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.scottandersonwebdesign.com/2016/05/03/Risk.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.scottandersonwebdesign.com/2016/05/03/Risk.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Is There Nothing Else?</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;As if the group project weekend wasn’t enough fun, now was time for another one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This time we are working for a client. A real one, not even pretend. A non-profit agency in Dripping Springs (right outside of Austin) is in need of an internal web app for their administrators, staff, and volunteers. We split into team of two for this assignment as well, so that the client would have more than just one design to choose from.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To figure out what the essential functions of the app were we met with one of their staff members. In the essence of time, let me list out what the client requested in the app:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Dashboard page&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Profile page&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Schedule page&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Printable schedule page&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Time off-request page&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Admin. approval request page&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Edits for profile page&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;New appointment edit page&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(multiple sizes are also needed, as the app needs to be responsive)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After noting everything they hoped for, it was time to ask them general questions so we could start thinking about possible directions our designs could go. What the environment is like on a day by day basis, words that describe the agency, and other logistical questions were just some of the things we asked.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And then there were the class requirements for this project. Like before, in the interest of time:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Sketches for each client requirement&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Stile Tiles&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Wireframes (all sizes all pages)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Mock Ups (all sizes all pages)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Web responsive style guide&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;At this point, the feeling of being overwhelmed creeped in upon me. Maybe my partner too.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Is there nothing else?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I found myself wondering, sarcastically, if anything had been left out. I just needed to breath, trust the abilities of myself and my partner, and get to work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We started with a Trello board and created the user stories in the backlog. We then assigned points to them based on the amount of time we believed each one would take. Immediately I began to feel better. Seeing the process mapped out not only put nerves at ease, but we felt a small since of accomplishment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At this time, I started thinking that Richard Dreyfuss’s character in &lt;em&gt;What About Bob?&lt;/em&gt; was on to something:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Tiny steps. Tiny steps. Breathe. Repeat. Tiny steps.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That board, and the agile process, was a saving grace. It allowed us not only the ability to map out the process, but to assign the work between the two of us. We could see the steps. Beginning with that process, and trusting it, was a huge reason we were able to complete the project on time and satisfactorily.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My partner and I, with the help of the Trello board, did a good job in dividing the work between us. First, we completed sketches for corresponding pages. Then, after looking at our ideas, merged them into one idea. We then moved into the wireframing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once we were ready to construct stile tiles, we decided to approach it the same way that we approached the sketches. We split them up, each doing two, and then decided we would come back and look at them all together.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My partner and I couldn’t help but laugh. We had each picked similar themes for each tile, but had come up with pretty different looks. After discussion, we merged what we thought were the best elements from all four into one stile tile that we were both happy with.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then came the mock-ups and style guide. David took the mock-ups, I took the style guide, and we worked side by side during the process. That way, we were constantly able to see where the other one was in their progression. We were also able to seek and offer feedback when it was needed. Eventually, we finished.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Phew…&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The client will decide next week which team has the design they wish to move forward with. My fingers are crossed, but in any event I am happy with what was accomplished.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 29 Apr 2016 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.scottandersonwebdesign.com/2016/04/29/NothingElse.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.scottandersonwebdesign.com/2016/04/29/NothingElse.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>TED Talk with Simon Sinek</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Simon Sinek, an author and speaker who specializes in leadership management, gave an interesting TED talk in 2009. Perhaps a little cheesy, sure. But I’ve always been a turophile at heart.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During that speech he described what he called the “Golden Circle.” He explained, that by looking at the circle we could better understand what makes successful people successful. To be a success, you need to start with the “Why” of what you do what you do. You do not start with the “What” as too many people make the mistake of doing. When you start with the “Why”, you are driven by resolve, and others can see the inspiration. Dr. Martin Luther King, Jr. was not driven by the “What” but by the “Why”, Sinek explains. That is why he has the famous, “I have a dream” speech, rather than the “I have a plan” speech.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To be successful, and to be successful long-term, you need to discover your “Why” and hold on to it tightly. It is not only what will make you a success but will keep your motor running for a very long time. If you lose the this, then you run the risk of running out of steam.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I decided to come to The Iron Yard and become a web designer. Why? To get a career and make money is fine, but it does not seperate me from anyone else, and will certainly not distinguish me from all the others applying for the same jobs I am in over a month. But knowing that I got into this field to be creative, to be challenged, and to be inspirational is my “Why”. No, I don’t think I will inspire the universe, my goals are not that lofty. But if I can inspire just a few others at a time over the course of my career, than I would consider that an accompishment, and myself a success.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.scottandersonwebdesign.com/2016/04/27/TED-Talk-with-Simon-Sinek.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.scottandersonwebdesign.com/2016/04/27/TED-Talk-with-Simon-Sinek.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Super Happy Weekend Fun</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Or as Iron Yard alumni call it: Hackathon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The official title of this past weekends homework is quite simply, “Group Project.” However, it did not take long for all the students to begin coming up with their more elaborate, perhaps appropriate names:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“My Brain is Fried Weekend”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“They Trapped Us Marathon”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Save Me Now Extravaganza”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But my personal favorite may be “Super Happy Fun Weekend.” This is most likely because it conveys both truth and sarcasm. Yes we were not exactly thrilled to be spending our entire weekend on campus hacking away. But truth be told, there were fun times as well. Going out to lunch, taking a break in the afternoon to play a card game, or laughing about finally figuring out why the code was broken all contributed to this fun.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But like all things there were important lessons learned as well. This project, I have learned in retrospect, was all about coding together as a team. This made the design aspect of the project more difficult. It’s easier when the only person you have to convince is yourself. It’s a whole different animal when you have to persuade a team to trust you on your idea(s). Yet, I remained confident in my plans. Without outwardly voicing it, I did my best to silently persuade my team to, “Trust me.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But that wasn’t the only challenge I faced.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Looking at the page in its entirety, once I have completed MVP, provides me a chance to go back and make corrections and improvements. By the time the JavaScript was working the way it needed to and I had finally completed the initial completion on designs I mocked-up, I did not have much time to sit and think about what would make the page look better.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Indeed, the page looked incomplete to me when we presented it. A professional site would have looked much better. Right before we presented it dawned on me what could make the site better:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;I need a more pronounced header in the whitespace!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But by that point, there were only 15 minutes or so on the timer. The site would have to remain as it sat, and be shown to everyone else none the less, no matter what I thought of how it looked. Not to mention that more improvements and corrections were going to have to be done before the site was anywhere near where I thought it should look. Yup, 15 minutes isn’t enough time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So what’s the lesson? I can’t wait to finish the MVP until other ideas come to the surface. I need to look at sketches and mock-ups and sketches long-before, and start deciphering what elements are missing or need to be tweaked.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also need to ask for more feedback and heed advice during the whole process. At this point it’s becoming clear to me that one can never ask for too much feedback. Having another pair of eyes definitely opens more doors for improvement. Want proof? A classmate had given me advice earlier in the weekend. What did he tell me? Put a more pronounced header in the site. Ugh, I had that advice staring me right in the face and didn’t pay enough attention to it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So don’t just ask for advice. Listen. At least try it even if you don’t think it’s going to work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lessons learned. And maybe next time I will not only have fun, but come away with a more complete, professional looking design.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 13 Apr 2016 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.scottandersonwebdesign.com/2016/04/13/Fun-Weekend.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.scottandersonwebdesign.com/2016/04/13/Fun-Weekend.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>It&#39;s Going</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Over the past 6 weeks people have been asking me, “How is it going?” I don’t usually have a great answer for them, and I chalk up some lame response like, “It’s Going.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Why am I saying this? Honestly, I give this answer so much now it’s as if I’m on auto-pilot. But I think I might provide this part-dismissive response for more than reason:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;“I’m working here!”&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is perhaps what I would like to say.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Back off. Leave me alone. If you’re going to interrupt, there better be food involved.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But that would be rude, so instead I reply, “It’s going.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I have been going through the learning process these past few weeks, it is easy to get very involved, very attuned to whatever it is I’m currently working on. Outside noises, smells, prying questions are just distractions I do not want to be interrupted with. And so me replying, “It’s going”, is my way of absently dismissing whoever is asking about the current progress (or lack thereof) I am experiencing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yet I have noticed that when this happens, it’s not as frequent as I may be thinking. If someone, such as my wife, comes up and asks how things are going it’s because she hasn’t seen me up and walking around for a while. I need to take that as a clue, that it’s time for a break. Doesn’t have to be a long one, but it is productive to take half an hour even and just stand up and walk around. Get my mind off of the project, protect my eyes from the screen, limit the carpal tunnel.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;“Not Sure….”&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is an honest and polite answer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;I don’t know how much I have left.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have learned that there is so much trial and error in coding. This past weekend we were working on a personal re-work of the LinkedIn home page. We were required to start with sketches, wireframe mockups, full mockups, and coding the page itself and making it responsive. We needed to include at least one JQuery in our code. And we needed to follow an existing style guide, mine was the U.S. Gov webpage. Once the page was coded and complete, we needed to do a rapid prototype with another style guide, which for me was the HealthCare.Gov webpage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I didn’t realize until Sunday afternoon that this was a lot to get done in a short amount of time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Getting the JQuery to work took me a while to figure out. During this time, I was asked, “How’s it going?” And honestly, I didn’t know. I could fix one id tag and it could work. I could be doing this completely wrong and need to start all over. I just didn’t know the answer for sure. And so, very politely, I answered, “It’s going.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;“I’m making progress”&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another honest answer, but more as a re-assurance to myself as opposed to someone asking me how everything was going.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This is taking a long time….but it’s getting done. Keep going. You can do this.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yes, coding is a lot of work. This past weekends LinkedIn project was a lot of work. The projects we have had to complete before this one were a lot of work. But I am doing this. I am coding. That’s awesome.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When a project may seem daunting, and it’s inevitable that there is going to be a lot of work to be done, I just need to know that I can do this. There were many steps to be completed on the LinkedIn project, but tenacity and hard work paid off. And when frustration, anger, restlessness, joy(the JQuery finally worked) all reared up, I told myself, “It’s going.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“It’s going” has become a powerful, small, phrase for me. Not for one of dismissive passivity towards inquiring friends and family, but as a motivational tool. One that reminds me of the importance of the project and the need for continued progress. But also, maybe most importantly, that I can do this and am learning and getting better everyday.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With that thought in mind, “It’s going” may be a phrase I use frequently going forward.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 07 Apr 2016 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.scottandersonwebdesign.com/2016/04/07/Its-Going.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.scottandersonwebdesign.com/2016/04/07/Its-Going.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Clearing my Head</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;In class today we had a visit from Clearhead, a company who happens to hold court in the office space adjacent to us at the Iron Yard. As luck would have it, they specialize in website validation and optimization. Their UX/UI team has agreed to meet us on Wednesday’s to see what we are working on and to provide feedback for us.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Awesome!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Wait. What if they think my work is terrible?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That was the first though going through my head. Maybe this fear is caused by a heavy case of imposter syndrome, thinking I don’t yet belong in the web designer sphere. Maybe one day. But not yet. No way I can have stuff yet that they think is great or shows potential.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(Now is the part where I talk about how Clearhead proved me wrong.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Patient, encouraging, and supportive. Those are some of the words I would use to describe their team. Never once did I feel judged or looked down upon. No, they were complementary. They mostly told us what they liked, describing ways they could see our designs progressing and improving. Never once did they absently dismiss anyones work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This taught me an important lesson. Constructive feedback is important in all industries, it’s an effective method for improving productivity and increasing return. But in web design it is very very important. There is a subjectivity present in this line of work which is not quite as prevalent in other industries. The look of one webpage will be interpreted by people from varying backgrounds and opinions, and getting their feedback is highly valuable. There are many factors that come into play when crafting a new design, and you are never going to be aware of all those factors. Others are going to have to bring them to your attention.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Going forward, it will be vital for me to be paying attention to every detail and factor I can, while being open to those I may not readily see and others do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thank you Clearhead for the help. And mostly, for being awesome.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 09 Mar 2016 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.scottandersonwebdesign.com/2016/03/09/Clearing-my-Head.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.scottandersonwebdesign.com/2016/03/09/Clearing-my-Head.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Getting Started</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I have now started at the Iron Yard. I can tell this will be an intensive 12 weeks, but I am up for the challenge. I am really enjoying the environment and the interaction with the instructors and other class members. Coding is awesome as well. Challenging, but awesome.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;HTML and CSS are difficult, but I think I am starting to develop a system for learning everything so fast. During lecture, I was making the mistake of trying to follow along with the instructors line for line, step for step. It didn’t matter if it was CSS, command line, or GIT, but I found myself falling behind. Eventually I figured out the best method, for me, was to keep the computer closed, and too watch them, listen, and ask questions if something initially seemed confusing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After lecture time comes lab time. This is my turn to try my hand at everything. And if I run into trouble (which I do) then I can always ask an instructor for help. But the best method of learning is by doing, which now clarifies why The Iron Yard allows the lab time in the afternoon. We need to have time to ourselves to figure it out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One thing I appreciate is that the instructors don’t always rush to give us an answer either. Before asking for help, I think it’s good to try everything I can by myself until I run out of ideas. But even then, when asking for help, the teachers will not just give an answer. Rather, they ask questions. By asking me questions, they are having me explore. Exploration, then, is the key to discovery. As a result, I usually am able to carve out my own path towards the solution, rather than relying on Abby, Aaron, Jess, or Justin to just tell me what to do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The only thing I don’t like so far is my commute from Salado to Austin. The traffic in this city is not my favorite…or anywhere for that matter. I can’t imagine there would be a traffic situation I would ever fall in love with…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In any case, I look forward to the weeks, challenges, and learning curves ahead.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 03 Mar 2016 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.scottandersonwebdesign.com/2016/03/03/Getting-Started.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.scottandersonwebdesign.com/2016/03/03/Getting-Started.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
